Guide to the Robert Hofstadter Papers SC0426
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Papers, Accession ARCH-1992-097
  - "Hadron Production In e+e- Annihilation from Square Root of S = 5.0 to 7.4 GeV" (empty folder), 1984 (Box 5, Folder 353)
  - "Latest Results from the Crystal Ball" (empty folder), 1984 (Box 5, Folder 354)
  - "Use of Synchrotron Radiation for Transvenous Imaging of the Coronary Arteries", 1984 (Box 5, Folder 355)
  - "Crystal Ball Results on psi 92s Radiative Decays" (empty folder), 1985 (Box 5, Folder 356)
  - "The Status of the Zeta (8.3)" (empty folder), 1985 (Box 5, Folder 357)
  - "Observation of Two Chi Beta States in Exclusive Radiative Decays of the psi (2s)" (empty folder), 1985 (Box 5, Folder 358)
  - "Observation of Three P States in the Radiative Decay of psi (2s)" (empty folder), 1985 (Box 5, Folder 359)
  - "A Symposium to Celebrate the Scientific Achievements of Robert Hofstadter," program, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 360)
  - "Measurement of the Decay Gamma (2s)—pi pi gamma (1s)" (empty folder), undated (Box 5, Folder 361)
  - "Prospects for Non-Invasive Angiography with Tunable X-Rays," Nulcear Instrument and Methods, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 362)
  - "A Personal View of Nucleon Structure as Revealed by Electron Scattering" (also includes handwritten draft), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 363)
  - Proposal to the National Science Foundation for Continuation of a Program in High Energy Physics, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 364)
  - "Nuclear Imaging In Medicine", 1986 (Box 5, Folder 365)
  - Talk for Junior Convocation at Stanford, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 366)
  - "The Angiography Program at Stanford" (conference presentation), 1985 (Box 5, Folder 367)
  - "Measurement of the Decay y(2S)—pi pi y(1S)," Physical Review D, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 368)
  - "Transvenous Coronary Angiography in Dogs Using Synchrotron Radiation", circa 1986 (Box 5, Folder 369)
  - "Transvenous Coronary Angiography in Humans Using Synchrotron Radiation", 1986 (Box 5, Folder 370)
  - "Synchrotron Radiation for Transvenous Coronary Angiography" (empty folder), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 371)
  - "Formation of Delta(980) and A2(1320) in Photon-Photon Collisions," SLAC Publication no. 3761, also published in Physical Review D, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 372)
  - Closing Remarks, Second Conference on Intersections between Particle and Nuclear Physics, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 373)
  - "Search for the Decay MU+ --> e+ y," Physical Review Letters, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 374)
  - "The Xb States in Exclusive Radiative Decay of the Gamma (2S)," SLAC Publication no. 3820, DESY-85-019, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 375)
  - "Search for Rare Muon and Pion Decay Modes with the Crystal Box Detector," Los Alamos Laboratory Publication no. LA-UR-86-3228, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 376)
  - "Use of a Tunable Quasimonoenergetic Gamma-Ray Beam for the Calibration of the EGRET Gamma-Ray Telescope in the Range 20-24,000 MeV", 1986 (Box 5, Folder 377)
  - "A Microscope for Nuclei and Nucleons", 1986 (Box 5, Folder 378)
  - "Properties of a Large NaI(Tl) Spectrometer for the Energy Measurement of High-Energy Gamma Rays on the Gamma Ray Observatory", 1986 (Box 5, Folder 379)
  - "Calibration of the EGRET High-Energy Gamma-Ray Telescope in the Range 20-10.000 MeV with a Tunable Beam of Quasimonoenergetic Gamma Rays at SLAC", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 380)
  - "Design and Performance of Modularized NaI(Tl) Detectors with Recatangular Crystal Elements: An Array of 49 and the Crystal Box", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 381)
  - "Behavior of Thallium Bromide Conduction Counters," Nuclear Methods and Instruments, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 382)
  - "The Electron Spectrum from B Meson Decays", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 383)
  - "The EGRET Project," Space Science Review, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 384)
  - "The Imaging Technology Used for Angiography at the Stanford Synchrotron Radiation Laboratory", circa 1985 (Box 5, Folder 385)
  - Nuclear Instruments and Methods -- multiple publications, undated (Box 5, Folder 386)
  - "Behavior of Thallium Bromide Conduction Counters," Physical Review D, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 387)
  - "Imaging of Coronary Arteries Using Synchrotron Radiation," Nuclear Instruments and Methods, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 388)
  - "William M. Fairbank" (speech), undated (Box 5, Folder 389)
  - "Synchrotron Radiation Coronary Angiography with Dual-Beam, Dual-Detector Imaging System," Nuclear Instruments and Methods, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 390)
  - "Recent Results in SYRDA at the Stanford Synchrotron Radiation Laboratory", circa 1990 (Box 5, Folder 391)
  - "Felix Bloch", 1965 (Box 5, Folder 392)
  - "The Synchrotron Radiation Angiography Program at the National Synchrotron Light Source", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 393)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1995-014
  - Awards and Honors
    Notifications, correspondence, promotional materials, and other documents related to honors and awards received by Hofstadter, as well as honors and awards for which he nominated colleagues.
    - Smithsonian Display, Scintillator, correspondence and technical drawings, circa 1977 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Nobel Foundation/Committee, publications, 1965, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "Who's Who in the West," Biographical Preparation Information, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Biographical Materials
    Includes Hofstadter’s curricula vitae and various versions of his bibliography; non-professional correspondence (autograph requests, thank you letters, family letters, and recommendations); as well as posthumous condolence letters sent to family members.
    - Letters of recommendation for former students [restricted], 1980-1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Requests for Autographs, circa 1961-1990 (Box 7, Folder 2-4)
    - Correspondence, Early Influences for Work, 1950, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - City College Alumnus Publication, 1962 Nov (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Lists of Hofstadter's Graduate Students, 1950-1977 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Social and Political Issues, 1967-1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Clippings
    Newspaper and magazine clippings sent to, or collected by, Hofstadter, regarding awards, honors and achievements; current events; and topics of interest.
    - EGRET on GRO, clippings and promotional material, 1978-1990 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      Scope and Contents note
      Note from Douglas Hofstadter is included.
    - Clippings and Publicity, Angiography, 1980-1986 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Clippings, California Scientist of the Year, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Lecture Announcements and Research Reviews, 1961-1975 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence
    Incoming and outgoing correspondence of Robert Hofstadter, arranged by correspondent or by topic.
    - Sodium Iodide, 1962-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Argonne National Labs re: scintillation and crystals research and publications, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence re: publications, 1960-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence re: speeches and lectures, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - R.Z. Bachrach (Xerox PARC), Site Visit and ICPS, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Academic Press re: publications, circa 1951-1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Addison-Wesley Publishers re: high-energy physics introductory textbook for high schoolers (never published), 1965-1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence re: Fusion, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Roy E. Rand, circa 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence/Reports -- re: Reviews of Scientific Instruments, Referee Reports, circa 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - C.D.G. Ravenhall, circa 1956-1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - R.S. (Stan) Safrata, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Abdus Salam (International Centre for Theroretical Physics), 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Dr. Giogio Salvini (Instituto Nazionale Di Fisica Nucleare, Rome), 1958-1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Shirleigh Silverman, 1960-1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence re: SLAC, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence re: E. Barrie Hughes, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence re: Proposal for 4 BeV Linear Accelerator by J. H. Fregeau, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence re: Nomination of W. M. Fairbank for California Scientist of the Year, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1963-1984 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, Faculty Appointments, 1964, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, R. Marshak re: Role in History of Particle Physics, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Note from Douglas Hofstadter is also included.
    - John Fluke Mfg. Co., Inc., Meeting Minutes, Board of Directors, 1986 Feb 13 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Schiff Memorial Committee, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Angiography
      - Correspondence, circa 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence and Publications, circa 1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence, circa 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence, Synchrotron Radiation Lab, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Catherine Wingate (National Institute of Health), 1983 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - E. Rubenstein, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
      - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - National Institute of Health Proposal, circa 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Hearst Foundation Grant, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Howard Hughes Medical Institute Grant Request, circa 1987 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Kaiser Foundation Grant, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - E. Rubenstein re: Angiography Manuscript, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Correspondence re: Business Plan and Budget, 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Bechtel Group, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - CA. Bienenstock (SSRL), circa 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Alexander von Humboldt Foundation re: Professor Bienlein, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - E. Rubenstein re: Development and Funding, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - Correspondence re: Exploration of Commercial Viability of Angiography, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Correspondence re: Conference Participation -- Medical Devices, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Roman W. DeSanctis (Harvard Medical) re: Synchrotron, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Department of Defense Energy Grant, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - National Institute of Health Grant Award, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - E. Rubenstein re: Angiography Group's Budget, Cost, and Meeting Minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - A.S. Berson (National Institute of Health) re: Meetings, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Harshaw Chemical Co.
      - Correspondence re: research, circa 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence re: research, circa 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence re: research, circa 1951-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Promotional material, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Publications relating to research, circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Description of contents from Douglas Hofstadter, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - GRO/EGRET
      - Correspondence, NASA, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence re: GRO Modifications, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, Peter Sturrock, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence re: TASC Specs for GRO/EGRET Project, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, Office of Naval Research, circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence re: NASA Audits, 1980 Nov (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, MDH Industries, Inc, circa 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, NASA re: Contract 452 (GRO/EGRET Funding), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, Joe Lepetich (HELP), 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, Charlie Campbell (Goddard Space Flight Center), 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence re: EGRET Meeting Minutes, 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence re: Contracts, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence re: Coded Aperture for EGRET, circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence re: Budgets, 1979-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
      - Correspondence, NASA, 1978-1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, TRW Defense and Space Systems Group, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence re: calibration of GRO/EGRET, circa 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence, J.M. Beggs, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence, General, circa 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence, Ball Aerospace/Western Labs, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Correspondence, NASA re: Astrophysics Paper Publication, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Dissertation re: EGRET on GRO by Lorna Campbell Finman, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
  - KMS Fusion
    Correspondence, research documents, reports, and promotional materials related to Hofstadter's work with KMS Fusion.
    - Promotional Material and Reports, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
    - Correspondence, Research, Reports, undated (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
      Kip Seigel's testimony, correspondence, memos, photographs of the apparatus, research notes, related documents, and clippings
  - Lecture Notes and Teaching Materials
    Includes Hofstadter's notes from two Princeton courses as well as a file on Quaid-T-Azam University, Pakistan.
    - Quaid-T-Azam University, Pakistan, circa 1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Princeton, "Solid Bodies" and "Quantum Mechanics.", 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Note from Douglas Hofstafter is included.
  - Legal Papers
    Legal documents and related materials, primarily related to patents.
    - Hofstadter vs. Sheldon, Patent Dispute, circa 1952 (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
    - Pringle vs. Schebatskoy, Scintillation Patent Dispute, circa 1956-1960 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Signal Corps, re: patent, etc, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Invention Disclosure Forms, K-Edge Subtraction Non-Invasive Angiography Using Monochromized Synchrotron Radiation, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Angiography Patents, 1981-1985 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - National Institute of Health Contract re: Angiography, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Research
    Includes drafts, notes, notebooks, raw data, graphical representations of findings, reports, and related documents. Also included are materials collected by or sent to Hofstadter due to their relation to his research, as well as related correspondence. There are also a few notebooks dating fromHofstadter's graduate study at Princeton.
    - Scattering notes, data, and related publications, circa 1965-1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Notebook, Sabbatical Year, Imperial College, London, circa 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Calculations on Finite Size of the Proton, data, figures, and related documents, 1955 July (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Research Notebook, Electron Scattering (Hydrogen), data, figures, and related documents, circa 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Note from Douglas Hofstadter is included
    - Electron Scattering, Various Elemental Nuclei, 1944-1955 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
    - Compton Effects/QED, research with John McIntyre, 1947-1949 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Discovery of Sodium Iodide Scintillators, data, notes, and related documents, circa 1948 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Notes on Bismuth Germanium Oxide (BGO) (photocopy, author unknown), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Princeton Physics Department, Quarterly Progress Reports for Army Signal Corps Project, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Universitat Bonn -- NaI(Tl), paper in German on crystals research and scintillation, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Notebook, Grad Course in Optics/Scintillator Work (Princeton), circa 1948 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Notebook, Course in Nuclear Physics, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Electron Scattering, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Electron Scattering, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Electron Scattering, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Collaborative Research on Electron Scattering, 250MeV, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Data and Notes, Drafts, 1939-1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Data re: Ca40 and Ca48 Scattering, circa 1967 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Course Notes, Princeton -- Quantum Mechanics (taught by H. Eyring and G. E. Kimball), circa 1930s (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - SPEAR and Magnetic Detectors, correspondence with Burton Richter, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Publications and research by close colleagues on related topics, 1953-1971 (Box 6, Folder 20-23)
    - Notebook, "Crystal Conduction Counters", 1985 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      Notebook is not in Hofstadter's handwriting. Original owner unknown; from Varian. Note from Douglas Hofstadter included.
    - High Energy Physics Laboratory funding proposals, 1969-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Angiography
      - Grant applications, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Angiography team notes, correspondence, and reports, circa 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
      - Team meeting minutes and agendas, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Site visit, proposal, notes, and related documents, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Synchrotron, notes and publications, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - NMR Studies, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - R. Pantell's notes on channeling radiation as a source of x-rays (photocopy), 1981 Sep 15 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Parallel work on angiography, clippings, notes, and related documents, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Animal care information, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence re: beam, lines, angiography, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Brookhaven Synchrotron, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Grants, financial documents, 1983-1988 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Talks with clinicians re: angiography, 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Proposal to SSRL for the Study of Iodide Dichromography with Monochromatic X-Ray Beams for Angiography, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - NASA and EGRET
      - Research/Presentation, GRO/EGRET, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Progress Reports for EGRET, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - EGRET on GRO, Reports and Publications, 1976-1989 (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
      - Ball Aerospace/Western Labs, Promotional Material and Reports on Total Absorption Shower, 1980, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Color Photographs of Satellite and Related Publications, GRO, circa 1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Norden Labs
      - Notebook, Norden Labs, circa 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Norden Labs, Technical Specifications, Altimeter, circa 1946 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Norden Labs Research, 1942-1946 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
      - Norden Labs Research and Correspondence., circa 1946 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        Includes letter of resignation and note from Douglas Hofstadter.
      - Notebook and Technical Specifications, Altimeter Development, circa 1943-1945 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
      - Norden Labs, circa 1946 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
  - Speeches and Presentations
    Drafts and final versions of talks given by Hofstadter, as well as supporting materials such as graphics and slides.
    - Optical Society of America, Boston, 1975 Oct (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - EGRET on GRO, Presentation Material, Gamma-Rays, etc., circa 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Angiography, slides, negatives and overheads, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Talks with Clinicians, "The Crystal Ball", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Angiography, slides and photographs, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Nobel Lecture, graphics, slides, and publications, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Lindau and Wurzburg, lecture material, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Lake Louise, Nuclear Physics, closing remarks, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Nobel Lecture, early version, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Acceptance Speech, Honorary Degree from Padova University, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Electron Scattering, Historical Account of Discoveries, draft, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Physics Department Colloquia, University of Illinois, 1986 Oct 22 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Introduction to 11th Schiff Lecture, 1982 Jan 19 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Nobel Lecture, graphics, slides, and publications, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Welcome Talk, International Conference on Physics of Semiconductors, San Francisco, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Travel and Conferences
    Files relating to Hofstadter's travel and conference attendance, including a 1983 digital radiology conference and a trip to Pakistan.
    - Digital Radiology Conference, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Pakistan Trip, preparation, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1999-150
  - Notes tipped in High Energy Scattering Tables (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2008-003
  - Audiovisual Materials
    - Physics 51, lectures 1 and 2, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 1)
    - Physics 51, lectures 3 and 4, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 2)
    - Physics 51, lectures 5 and 6, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 3)
    - Physics 51, lectures 7 and 8, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 4)
    - Physics 51, lectures 9 and 10, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 5)
    - Physics 51, lectures 13 and 14, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 6)
    - Physics 51, lectures 15 and 16, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 7)
    - Physics 51, lectures 17 and 18, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 8)
    - Physics 51, lectures 19 and 20, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 9)
    - Physics 51, lectures 21 and 22, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 10)
    - Physics 51, lectures 23 and 24, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 11)
    - Physics 51, lectures 25 and 26, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 12)
    - Physics 51, lectures 1 and 2, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 13)
    - Physics 51, lectures 3 and 4, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 14)
    - Physics 51, lectures 5 and 6, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 15)
    - Physics 51, lectures 7 and 8, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 16)
    - Physics 51, lecture 9, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 17)
    - Physics 51, lectures 10 and 11, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 18)
    - Physics 51, lectures 12 and 13, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 19)
    - Physics 51, lectures 14 and 15, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 20)
    - Physics 51, lectures 16 and 17, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 21)
    - Physics 51, lectures 18 and 19, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 22)
    - Physics 51, lectures 20 and 21, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 23)
    - Physics 51, lectures 22 and 23, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 24)
    - Physics 51, lectures 24 and 25, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 25)
    - Physics 51, lecture 26, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 26)
    - Physics 51, lectures 1 and 2, 1981 Jan; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 31, Item 27)
    - Commencement address, "The Free Spirit in the Free University," City College of New York (CCNY), circa 1963; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 31, Item 28)
    - Physics 51, lecture 3, 1983 Jan 10; 1 videotape(s) (beta) (Box 31, Item 1)
    - Physics 51 lecture, 1983 Jan 24; 1 videotape(s) (beta) (Box 31, Item 2)
    - Laser fusion lecture, 1978 May 5; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 31, Item 3)
  - Awards and Honors
    Notifications, correspondence, promotional materials, and other documents related to honors and awards received by Hofstadter, including the Nobel Prize and California Scientist of the Year, as well as various honorary degrees.
    - John H. Finley Award, City College of New York (95th Annual Dinner, Nobel Laureate Night), 1975 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Nobel Prize, Invitation and Press Kit, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Rontgen Medal (Wurzburg), circa 1985 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Various Awards and Honors, circa 1986 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Galileo/Nobel Celebration, San Remo and Rome, 1983 May (Box 25, Folder 5)